Man, I had a small accident three months ago
.  Luckily, nothing happened to me
.  But my car was badly damaged.
Both doors on the right side of my car were
damaged.  There was even a
hole in the front door.
I'll show you a photo of the car for verification.
Actually, as you can see, the car tire is
completely damaged, but I'm
not just telling you this because
immediately after the accident, I obviously
called my insurance company and
explained the situation, but what happened next was
very disturbing. In this video, I will not only
tell you my experience of making an insurance claim, but also
tell you which insurance to buy in 2025.
Let's see what happened after the accident. Naturally, I
called my insurance company and
as you can see, the front door was badly
damaged, but the back door was
in repairable condition.  The insurance
company said that they
will replace the front door and repair the rear door
but will not do anything about the tire. I said okay.
I just requested them to get the car
repaired at the authorized dealership of the car company. They said and I quote
that in the authorized dealership
you will have to pay the GST payment from your pocket
and I have a 100% cashless
claim policy. They said that if you get it
repaired at our preferred dealership, then
only the paper charge will be charged which is around
Rs. 12 and you will not have to pay any other charges.
They
said okay, do as you see fit.
I dropped my car and after two
weeks I got a call that the front door
replacement has not been received and hence the
rest of the repairs have not been done. I asked how much more
time it will take. They said that they
cannot say anything for a month or two months. At that moment
I was very, very angry and at that
moment I decided that this issue must be escalated
but the senior juniors did not care at all
so I called the senior of the insurance company.  I
reached out to the management on LinkedIn
and I casually mentioned B Kefli there. I don't know
what they did,
but still my issue was not resolved.
They stuck to their stance and
finally, after two months, my car was ready
.  When I went to pick up my car, the
mechanic there
told me, "Madam, where are you stuck? We
work with all companies."
I was literally shocked to hear that you have a lot of insurance,
man, I
professionally evaluate the best insurances, if
I can make this mistake,
what will happen to normal customers and what will happen,
so I decided to do proper research and
tell you the top three to four best names so that you don't get
confused like me.
You must be thinking, why did I have
insurance with which I had such a
bad experience?
I will not defame that company directly by taking its name,
but unfortunately that company is going to be rejected from my final shortlist
and now I will
tell you with which company I am going to finalize my policy. Come on, man,
first of all, let's talk about some basics.
Now, basically, there are two types of car insurance,
third party and comprehensive.
Third party means that in the event of an accident, the third party damages will be
covered, but the
damage caused to your own car will
not be covered. In comprehensive,
you get both the damage to your own car and the third party damages.  Usually you have to
take comprehensive insurance, the
premium is high, but you
get peace of mind by taking insurance. Now that you understand
that you should take comprehensive insurance, but
you have to take some downs in it,
I will tell you one by one. First comes
Returns to Invoice or RTI. RTI means that
if your car gets major damage
or gets stolen, the insurance company will
pay the original invoice amount of the car, which
includes the ex-showroom price of the car plus insurance plus RC. If you do
not take RTI cover, then
in case of major damage, you will
get the IDV of the car. IDV means Insured
Declared Value. For a new vehicle,
IDV is 95 percent of the ex-showroom price,
but for a three to four year old vehicle,
you will get only 60 to 65 percent of the car
value. Due to depreciation, as the age of the car
increases, the car  Depreciation happens,
so if the car is five years old, then
the value will decrease by 50 percent, but
if you take RTI, you will
get the full value of the car, but this cover is only
available for the first three years. The next
important one is Zero Depreciation Cover
or Zero Depreciation Cover, also called Bumper to Bumper,
and you get this for five years.
Now you must know that after
buying a car, its value keeps
decreasing due to depreciation. Suppose you bought a car for Rs 10
lakh and after five years due to depreciation,
its value becomes Rs 1 lakh, which is
50% of the original value. Suppose after five years,
some damage occurs to the car, which costs
Rs 50,000. If there is no Zero Depreciation Cover, the
insurance company will reimburse you 50% of your money,
i.e. Rs 25,000, but if you have Zero
Depreciation Cover, you will
get a claim for your 50,000. Zero Depreciation Cover  If you take it,
your annual premium will increase by 15 to 20%
but only if you can afford it.
Consumables
come in the form of nuts, bolts, AC, coolant, ball bearings, grease, etc.
Normally, these parts are in the front part of the car, which means that if
damaged, this
part has the most impact and can easily
become 10 to 15 percent of your overall expenses. This don is usually very cheap, 500-600,
so I recommend that you definitely
take it. It is all the necessary dons. Apart from this, there are
many dons like engine
protection, tire cover, key and lock set
replacement. All these are not very important,
but you can take them if you feel the need.
In my accident case, the tire was completely torn,
but unfortunately I did not have this cover,
so I had to spend 5 thousand separately. So
if you want complete protection, you can
consider this don.
Before looking at the best car insurance companies, let's
recap the most important one.  The point
is that you
must take comprehensive car insurance, not third party,
and along with that, take three benefits: Return to
Invoice, Zero Depreciation, and Consumables.
You can take extra benefits like Engine Protect, Tire Cover, etc. as per your wish
.  So let's see
what are the best insurance companies in 2025
?  First, let's look at the claim
settlement ratio and network garages of all the companies
.  As a hygiene filter, I
remove companies whose network garages are
less than 4000.  Because if the network garage is
not nearby, it becomes a big problem.
You have seen my experience.  By the
way, my old insurance company is also
removed from this filter.  If you want to
guess the name of that company, be
sure to tell me in the comments.  After
applying this filter I am left with only 10 companies
.  Now let's look at the ICR, i.e. ICR, of this company
.  But
before that, let's understand what ICR is and why it is
important.  ICR
means how much claim amount was paid out of the total premium amount collected by the insurance company in a financial
year
?   For
example, if the company's ICR is 78%, the
insurance company
pays 78 claim payments for every ₹1 in premium.   The
ICR provides information about the financial health of the company
.  If the ICR is more than 100%, it
means the company is paying too many claims.   This
means that the insurer's financial health is
not strong and it may incur losses.   If
the ICR is less than 70%, the company
is making a lot of profit and for this they may be
rejecting more claims or
charging higher premiums from people.
So ideally you should
choose a company with an ICR between 70 and 100
.  For perfect clarity, let's
compare the data from the last two years.  Thi yaar
almost all the companies ICR
was within the desired range but for hygiene purpose we
removed those companies which
were less than 70% almost every year so
now we have six companies left now it is
very difficult to choose just one company
because everyone has different needs right in it
I will tell you my top four picks
HDFC Ergo ICICI Lombard
SBI and Tata AIG out of these four I have
finalised ICICI Lombard out of these four
I have finalised ICICI Lombard
so in future my car insurance will be
with ICICI
I will
definitely share my experience with it in the next videos if
you liked this video even a little bit
then please comment that this is the best
video on car insurance our hard work will be
successful and yes you will
guess the name of my previous insurance company or not guess
and let me know in the comment thank you